Welcome to another week in AI and this
week has been very colorful. We have
creative tools that you can use for
non-creative things like brainstorming
and ideiation. And then there's a bunch
of releases from China across the board
including a top tier model that intakes
videos as a part of your prompt and you
can use it for free. So we have all that
and so much more in this week's episode
of AI News. You can use the show that
takes all of the AI releases from this
week filters for the ones that matter
and then we get to look at them
together. Okay. So here we have an
application of which we've seen
versions, but every time Google Apps
does something new, I just get excited
cuz they do some of the most creative
interfaces in all of AI. And now they're
doing something they call a mixboard,
which is nanobanana on the back end and
a creative interface on the front. Let's
just get right into trying this. I'll
create a new project. And by the way, if
you want to access this, you need to be
in the US. So yes, I am using a VPN
right here. But essentially, this gives
you this creative mixboard where you can
easily combine multiple ideas. So, I
like this one. How about we make
something fun? Show me cats with hats.
Okay, now it's going to generate
multiple images. So, there's a bunch of
cats with hats right here. Look at that.
It didn't just generate three of them.
It made like a whole bunch. Okay, let me
upload an image, too. How about a taco
hat? Yes. Okay, there you go. We have
the taco hat. But honestly, this could
be really useful for marketing purposes
where you just have different branding
assets and different products in here.
And I really like the way it just
created a bunch of them. Like, this is
great. Okay. And then with shift I can
select multiples. So I could for example
take this cat and this image and then be
like combine them. And then it's going
to use nanobana to combine them. Okay,
that's not perfect. Let me try different
things. What if I just take these four
cats right here and I say family
picture. Oh, and sure enough, there it
is. That actually worked super well.
Okay. Wow. Very quickly, we're arriving
at quite the fun art board here. And
well, this might be a fun example.
Seriously, if you put in your logos and
just a bunch of different images from
the internet and then you generate a
bunch of images in here, too. As you saw
with a cat with a head, I just got 50
new images. You can start mixing and
matching these things. An interface that
is not very typical and quite intuitive.
At least I find that myself. Create a
collage. What would it do with all the
images? Oh, wow. Look at that. So, truly
this is quite powerful. And mind you,
I'm just logged in on a free account
here doing all of this. Okay. What
happens if I say more like this? Wa!
Three completely different compilations
and it's all cats with different hats.
Honestly, I kind of like these. I might
have to print some cat with hat art. I'm
thinking this little guy would motivate
me to work hard on a regular. No doubt
about it. And just so we don't end on
cats with hats, I'm going to go to this
plan a party preset. And I'm going to do
a cozy tennis themed party in my living
room. And ah honestly, this is a
fantastic way to brainstorm, too. I
mean, come on. If you need ideas for
something, this might just be one of the
best workflows out there. No ideas for
decoration, ideas for activities. So, I
like this. This is not the first angle
that I showed you where you can use it
to create assets, but you could just use
it for inspiration. So, now I could
maybe take some of these activities like
this one, this one, this one, tell it to
generate more ideas for tennis themed
party, and now I'm using images to
generate new ideas. And I myself as a
visual learner would much prefer this
from a wall of text that you would get
inside of Chat GPT. But if you want
text, you can get that, too. Like these
right here. Tennis trivia challenge,
best match viewing party, do-it-yourself
wristband decorating station. And again,
all of this is free. Pretty impressive.
All right, for the next one, we have a
release coming out of China. Quen
released six new models. And usually, we
wouldn't spend too much time on this
because, hey, there's many models out
there, and China is competing, releasing
good ones. They're not going to be
life-changing. You know that by now. But
what I was interested in is that if you
go to this website, chat.quen.ai, AI,
you have well all these new models, but
also their Max model supports video
upload. Interesting. So, I'm just going
to give this a quick spin to see how
that works in practice. I'm just going
to pick out some random video from my
downloads folder. I'm just going to do
this one. It's just me drinking water,
doing a few gestures. We'll use it later
on, but I'll upload it here and then
I'll ask it describe precisely what you
see. Okay, it's going to upload.
Meanwhile, we rock out.
enough. Okay, back to it. So, let's just
send this and see if it describes it
precisely. Wow. So, it's generating
slowly, but it has a video and this is
the max model. This is very precise. So,
it is what I hoped for. Neither Chachi
nor Claude have this right now. You can
find this in Gemini, but this is the
first big alternative to it. I like it.
Look at that. The scene custom medium
close-up shot of a young man sitting in
what appears to be a gaming chair. dark
brown, neatly styled hair, a light
beard, and a mustache, and is wearing a
white, long-sleeved button-down shirt.
The background is softly lit, and
slightly out of focus. I kind of enjoy
this description of an AI of the scene
that I see here day by day, and you see
it week by week. White panel, doors on
either side of him, a lamp emitting warm
light, surfboard shaped mirror on the
wall. That's not a mirror. That's an
actual surfboard. Anyway, you get the
point that this actually works. All the
gestures are described in here. Arm
crossing. So if you need to work with
video as context, yeah, there you go.
Quenfreeax is your second option next to
Gemini. And that's it. If you care to
learn about the other models that are
good but nothing special, you can check
out their blog post. So for the next
story, we have something that I was
actually excited to try because
sometimes we get these video models, but
also these animation models where you
give it a video and it reenacts it. And
these have been getting steadily better.
The newest one is from Alibaba and it's
called One 2.2 Animate. Now, I did go in
here and pay like a $1.50 to load 30
credits to try this out. So, you cannot
do this for free, but what it does in
theory is I can upload a target video,
which I will do. It's the video that I
showed you earlier of me just doing
different gestures. Okay. And there's a
time limitation on it. So, we'll just go
from here all the way to here. This
should work. Confirm. And now I need to
pick a character. Now, during the
preparation of this video, we were
thinking, what kind of character would
be good? And I don't know why, but we
just landed on Conor McGregor. So, I'm
going to give it a picture of Connor
over here. And then it should turn me
into Connor. Let's use up 20 credits,
which is like a dollar here, to make
this character swap app. And hope this
works. Please try a different image.
I'll try this. Okay, it's generating.
Should be done in about 6 minutes. 15
minutes later. So, I tried three times
with Conor McGregor. It didn't work. So,
now instead I'm going to use an image of
Rocky cuz why not? Let's actually do the
pro mode and generate. So, this is Eigor
Stallone. Let's have a look.
Wow, that's unbelievably good. Holy
moly. Yeah, so this works. I don't know.
This cost me $150, but I'd say that's
well worth it. Honestly, not sure what
else to add. There's other tools like
this, but my feeling is this one works
even better than what I've seen before.
Yeah. Um, thank you, China, for turning
me into Rocky and saving me all that
time in the gym. And additionally to
this model that allows you to input a
video and an image and make the
character, they also released a
competitor to V3 Free. It does video
generation plus audio generation. And
what we figured right away is that hey,
we wonder how well it performs compared
to V3 that is state-of-the-art
currently. So we did the most logical
thing. We ran the same prompt in both of
them. And now let's have a look at what
these look like in 1 2.5 and V3.
>> This is not just my story, it's ours. If
we stay silent now, who will speak
later?
>> And in that moment, I knew everything
had to change. Not just for me, but for
all of us.
>> So, V3 actually has this like robotic
tin can like sound that is so typical to
it whenever you see it on Instagram or
whatever. I don't think one has that.
>> It's ours.
>> It's not perfect, but the voice is
better. Let's have a look at another
one. One 2.5.
[Music]
>> It's okay. Don't love the audio.
Yeah, this ambient sound is just a bit
better here. None of them are perfect.
And then a dragon flying towards
medieval kingdom.
It's okay.
>> A dragon soared above the castle as the
kingdom held its breath.
>> Okay, that's epic. And even the video is
better. So, I can tell you from what
I've seen across Twitter and in their
blog post, this video model is very
good, but it's not quite as good as V3.
But the audio in some cases, especially
when it comes to voices, seems cleaner.
It's just good to see more competition
in the market. And yeah, if you need a
video model that also does audio, 1 2.5
is something you should definitely
consider. And as we're talking about
video models, there's also another video
model, namely Cling, releasing their 2.5
Turbo API. We ran it through our various
tests and as per usual, Clink performs
super well. You can see some of the
comparisons to the other leading models
here on screen right now. Character
consistency is good on our little monkey
with a boat test prompt here. This is
the first time I see the monkey
splashing water at the boat, which is
very courageous. Water is notoriously
hard for all video models. And then we
have Mr. Slo and his cocktail just
straight chilling right here in the
pool. It's a good model. It's cheaper
and it's faster than the ones before,
but other than that, not really a
breakthrough. So, let's see what's next.
So, for our next story, it's really a
combination of two things. It's one a
new story that went viral this week that
relates to AI audio, and two, a new AI
audio version of one of the most popular
apps out there, Suno. So, they released
V5. I would call it an upgrade to what
we had before. There's more clarity. The
vocals sound even better. But comparing
it to some of the other models out there
like 11 Labs music or UDO, it's becoming
really hard to tell what's better.
Nevertheless, I want to tell you about
the story that happened this week and
we're going to have a quick peek at a
song that V5 generated just so you can
hear how good this actually sounds. But
the story I've been referencing is
actually something that hit the
mainstream. It's this artist called
Monet, I suppose it's pronounced. It's
basically a American lyricist with an AI
alter ego that uses AI to produce her
songs. So, she writes the lyrics and
then she uses AI to vocalize them and
create the entire audio. And I got to
tell you, I had a quick listen here in
preparation for this video and wow, it
sounds really good. The lyrics are
impressive. You can really tell that
these are not AI written lyrics. But
have just a quick peek at this. I think
most people hearing this on the radio
would not know this is AI. We're just
gonna play a few seconds so this doesn't
get demonetized. It's really good. The
production is incredible and it used
tools similar to Suno V5 here. So, with
that being said, I guess we're only
going to see more and more AI artists.
And now, let's have a look at this new
V5 version. If I just open up my Suno
here, there's various songs that were
produced with it. And I will have a
quick listen to one of them right here.
Let's have a quick listen. So cozy.
[Music]
>> Honestly, you just can't tell anymore.
And I don't think I'm qualified enough
to really tell the difference between
all these various models at this point.
It just sounds good. So if you used to
play around with Suno, give it a second
look cuz the upgrades from V3 over V4
and 4.5 and now 5, they're really
audible. It just doesn't sound like AI
anymore. And artists realize that. So,
we're just in a world where AI art is
becoming a part of the mainstream and
there's no going back. Okay, so to round
this video out, I'll be showing you all
of this week's quick hits. This is the
segment where we look at all the stories
that maybe don't deserve multiple
minutes of testing and reviewing, but
you should still know about them. And
we'll start out with a brand new arena
that ranks different models. There's
many of these, but honestly, I just
realized who even runs these platforms
like Ella Marina. They're super popular.
But now, Scale AAI released their own
version of this arena. And
interestingly, so GPT5 Chat actually
ranks as the number one model with Opus
4.1 on the second spot. I always like to
get more leaderboards. We follow most of
them and let those opinions influence
our own usage and recommendations. Next
up, we have a OpenAI released and it's a
new API endpoint, GPT5 Codeex. It's the
model that powers their codec that has
become extremely popular over the past
weeks. It was the lead story of last
week's news you can use video and now
you can directly access this coding
focused model directly through the API.
Nice. They're really trying to out
compete and anthropic here with their
coding focused models because before
this their models were the gold standard
for coding. Also, Google is putting AI
everywhere. At least they're trying to
and seeing how users respond. And that
trend continues this week with this
brand new AI integration into Google
Chrome. So if you update it, you should
have this brand new AI button on the top
right. For now, this is US only. But
essentially, you just have this AI
button, which by the way, this little
sparkle has become the gold standard,
right? That's sort of like the logo of
AI across the internet. Anyway, this
little sparkle on the top right opens up
various AI options and you can use
Gemini from wherever you are. You don't
need to open a separate tab. You can
interact with the entire worldwide web
just like this. And chances are most
people watching this video are actually
watching it from Google Chrome just
because how damn popular this browser
is. And now all of it has AI. Notion 3.0
zero released agents and a whole bunch
of integrations. And I think this is
actually quite interesting. As you know,
I myself am a power user of notion. I
have my entire company knowledge base,
all the video production stuff,
everything in notion, even my personal
to-do lists. And now it all integrates
into each other. I think the main thing
that they did here is that it allows you
to create these different agents with
different knowledge documents. And in
other apps, I usually export the
markdown files from notion and bring
them in. Here I don't have to do that.
So I'll be exploring this more and more
over time. and Notion actually reached
out to partner on a video. So, we might
be doing a deep dive onto everything
that this has to offer. I'm genuinely
curious to learn all about this myself.
And the last quick hit this week is more
of a notification, and that is that if
you're using entropic models, up until
now, they were very clear that they
won't train on your data. Well, as of
September 28th, that is changing. Now,
this becomes a setting that you have to
disable yourself. So, if you don't want
them to train on your data, you will
have to go into the settings and
proactively uncheck the field that says
they're allowed to use it. Easy to miss,
but now you know. And that is pretty
much everything we have for this week.
One last note is that there's a lot of
rumors about major releases coming up
soon. So, if you haven't done so yet,
subscribe to the channel cuz we'll be
covering all of it. And with that being
said, my name is Igor and I hope you
have a wonderful